Finding Aid for Allyn Ravitz papers, 1973-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Allyn Ravitz papers 1973-1997
Ravitz, Allyn.
0.6 linear feet
2009028 Aa 2
Feminist attorney from Detroit, Michigan. Topical files relating to cases in which she was involved; organizational activities, especially the Feminist Federal Credit Union; and feminist issues and interests, including credit and housing discrimination, sexual harassment, etc.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Allyn Ravitz (donor no. 10141 ) and came to the library in 2009.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Allyn Ravitz was a graduate of the University of Detroit School of Law in 1972. Soon thereafter she became legal counsel for Metropolitan Detroit NOW and active in various women's rights causes. In 1974, she helped form the first all-women's credit union in the country, the Feminist Federal Credit Union. Within one year, the credit union had issued more than a third of $1 million in loans to women. At the same time, Ravitz and others were trying to pass legislation to change Michigan's credit laws. Ravitz also helped change the Fair Housing Act so women would not be discriminated against on the basis of sex, age, or because they were mothers with children.
The Allyn Ravitz collection includes subject files relating to her activities and to her overall interest in women's rights. Of especial interest are her files on the Feminist Federal Credit Union and her support of legislation to prohibit sex discrimination in credit practices. In addition to clippings and published material, the collection includes correspondence, organizational materials, certificates of appreciation, and miscellaneous.
Subjects:
Feminist Federal Credit Union.; Feminists--Michigan.; Ravitz, Allyn.; Sex discrimination against women--Michigan.; Women lawyers--Michigan.; Women's Defense and Education Committee.
- Topical Files
  - Biography, certificates, and clippings with mention of her activities, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Credit Bill, 1973-1975 (Box 1)
    (legislation to prohibit sex discrimination in credit practices)
  - Feminist Federal Credit Union
    - 1973 (Box 1)
    - 1974 (Box 1)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Great Lakes Steel Maternity bias, 1984 (Box 1)
  - HUD Case, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Mabel Dingeman Dinner (Box 1)
  - Michigan Women's Political Caucus, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Sexual Harassment (clippings, publications, etc.)
    - History, misc. (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 1)
    - Faye Nale case and related (Box 1)
  - Speaking Engagements, Correspondence, etc. (Box 1)
  - Violence against Women (Box 1)
  - Winkelman's Credit Application, 12/1973 (Box 1)
  - Women Who Move Detroit-engagement calendar, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Women's Defense & Education Committee, 1975-1977, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Women's Equality Day; women and the law (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 1)